Ten wants to end it in one go
Riichi
This is the last hand!
By whatever means necessary
Cheating fucks
I will make you regret that Riichi
Ten is aiming for both a SanSyoku and Chanta at the same time
and he's got to get a 1 Sou to get it
But
We're in a tough spot
A Chanta SanSyoku
Going for them both at once!
I'm in Tenpai with a 3 sided wait
It's only a matter of time before I draw my winning tile!
Ten's wait is without doubt for a  1 or 4 Sou
And if he gets a 1 Sou it's Chanta and SanSyoku
But even with just the 4 Sou
If he carries additional Dora it's a Dealer win
It's a Tsumo
混全帯么九、三色同順、
A Chanta SanSyoku!
The Yaku are Cleared!
天さん勝ちました！
Ten, You've won!
待たんかい
Just hold on now
まだわからん
We don't know just yet
ひろゆき
Hiroyuki
俺はまだ
I have not yet...
flipped the tiles
Right now
I've got a Menpin Tsumo Chanta SanSyoku
as well as an Ipeikou and 2 Dora
that's 10 Han
The upper limit of a Baiman win
この手に
In this hand...
裏ドラが一つでも乗れば三倍満
If I should carry even ONE Ura-Dora, it's a SanBaiMan win
お前が飛ぶ
It knocks you out
HA HA HA HA
BOTTOM TEXT
なんや
How about that
気がついとったんかい
Didn't you notice?
強運も度が過ぎりゃ
Your remarkable luck struck once too often
毒に転嫁するんやで
and it brought poison with it
ええか
DIDN'T IT?
クリアは達成するが
You may have cleared the Yaku
同時に箱割れ者も出し、
and at the same time knocked out a teammate who has no points
勝ちと負けの条件を同時に達成する可能性があるんや
It's possible to complete both the conditions of victor and defeat simultaneously
すべてはそこの
And now everything
裏ドラが決する
Is decided by the Ura-Dora
天！
Ten!
開けてみい
Reveal it!
のらなければ東の勝ち、
If we don't carry the Ura-Dora the East team wins
頼む！
Please!
のらないでくれ
Don't get it!
天、
Ten
ひとつ教えてくれ
Just tell me one thing
なんでそんな危ない勝負に出たんや
Why, in such a dangerous match...
おどれの手、
Your hand...
黙聴でもよかったはずや
It would have been better to NOT have declared Tenpai
己の背後の扉を固く締め
I barred the door behind me
自ら退路を絶つ
cut off my own retreat
立直をしなかったら恐らく
If I had not declared Riichi, in all probability...
お前らの勝ちだった
it would have meant your victory
お互いがしのぎを削っている以上
More than simply sharpening blades for battle
奪い取る気がなければ勝ちはない
without the will to take it, there is no victory
相手のミスを待つような麻雀では道は開けない
Mahjong where you simply wait for your opponent to make a mistake does not open the way
原田、
Harada,
お前もわかっているだろうが
I think you understand that just as well as I
もはやこの勝負、
Already this contest,
理では勝てない
can't be won by simple logic
あそこで退けば
That ignores something
お前らとの危うい均衡が崩れ、
your delicate balance crumbles,
勝負を決する大切な何かを失っていた
and the most important thing to decide the contest is lost
そう感じて
You feel that
直感に従ったまで
and instinctually obey it
ただ、
Only,
それだけだ
that's all there is
これは引き分けということですが？
Is this some kind of... draw?!?
USELESS FUCK
ここに辿り着くんにどんだけの
労力と時間を使ったと思っとんねん
I did not think it would take this exceptional level of effort or time to arrive at this point
決着は付ける
Let's settle this once and for all
天、
Ten...
二人だけで決めようや
Let's decide this between us two alone
ワイはオドレを倒したい
I want to defeat your personally
せやからもう誰もまぜん！
Yeah, with no one else to muddle things!
二人麻雀や
1V1 Mahjong
Agreed
Arrange it
俺には
You know...
原田の気持ちが少しわかる気がする
I kinda think I know how Harada feels
恐らくやつは
In all probability
時を追いかけている
he's chasing a moment
時？
A moment--?
ああ、
Yeah
俺も似たような気持ちを
He feels like me in that...
ここ何年か抱えてきたからわかるんだ
I understand the burden he's carried for so many years
やつは上り詰めたいのさ
He's wanted to get to the top
生涯に一度で良いから
It's the only good in his entire life
最高の時を迎えたいんだよ
and he wants to reach that pinnacle
それはつかの間で
and in the moment when he's got it
すぐ彼方に消えてしまうような虚ろな感覚、
he soon feels the hollowness of it slipping away
しかし一度近くまで行った人間にとって、
but he's only human, and wants to reach it one more time
その充足は圧倒的
that feeling of satisfaction is so overwhelming
原田も恐らく
Harada, I dare say...
病気よ
Is very sick
俺らにはもう、
Honestly...
あまり見当たらないんだ、
I've scarcely seen anyone more so
他に人が生きる理由なんて
What else has he to live for?
一瞬でいい。ともかく
Just that single moment. One way or another
最高を感じたいんだ
He wants to feel that high again
俺も原田も
And to both Me and Harada...
もう近くまで来ているのかもしれないな
that might be coming sooner than you think
First and explanation of the 1v1 Mahjong rules
From time to time...
九州の親分衆とたま
For a group of Kyuusyu Bosses
a mahjong a little changed
映像での説明
This video will explain the rules
Yo
Yessir
100,000 points
Tsumo!
When you win you take points from here
When the match is over
This two player Mahjong
前半ステージA
The first part is Stage A
And the 2nd part Stage B follows
First, stage A
This is like 4 person Mahjong with only 2 players
Chii
You can declare Chii off the other player
It differs as follows
Whether your hand is open or closed...
if you're in Tenpai you must declare it
Tenpai
If your hand is closed you may also declare Riichi
Riichi
Thus ends stage A
This Mahjong
At the point when either player declares Tenpai
The method of play previously followed completely ends
consequently speed is the greatest advantage
The 2nd part is Stage B
The side who hasn't declared Tenpai
chooses his opponent's next two draws
the two designated tiles are presented
if there's a winning tile among the two
this results in a draw
the side who would win
without exceptions must show their hand
this is to protect against false Tenpai declarations
If there aren't any winning tiles among the two
the side declaring tenpai has the right to 5 draws
Tsumo!
If they haven't completed their hands in 5 draws
they go back to the start
There is a single special rule
If you make SanSyoku with 2 Man
Tsumo!
Other rules follow in that manner
なるほど、
Of course
これは勝負を打つものとしての強運、
It's a style of play addressing luck,
そして
二人の人間としての力、
器が裁かれる
なるほど、
この二人麻雀は待ちが悪いほど有利なんだ
多面待ちは
一つの牌を当てれば済む
ので看破しやすい
単騎待ちなどは
一つの牌を当てなければならない
看破しにくい
原田が立直すれば
すべては水泡に帰す
原田、
またせたな
聴牌を宣言する
馬鹿な！
なぜ萬子？
なぜ萬子と見抜く？
天さんの捨て牌から
萬子とは想像しづらい
萬子を嫌った索子の混一色と読むのが定石